#### Contact

089038, Barcelona. 622580074 (Mobile) sarony11@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/saulfernandez-martinez (LinkedIn)

### Top Skills

Terraform

Grafana

prometheus

#### Languages

**English** 

Spanish

Catalan

#### Certifications

SRE and DevOps Engineer with Google Cloud Professional Certificate

Kubernetes for Developers IT Essentials

Kubernetes for Administrators IT Essentials

Become a Docker Administrator

## Saul Fernandez Martinez

Platform Engineer DevOps padawan. Automating the dark side of the infrastructure.

Barcelona, Catalonia, Spain

## Summary

AWS/GCP △# | Docker, Kubernetes # | Terraform | Prometheus, Grafana, Loki, Graylog##

"In any technological project as in any other field, psychology and the study of human behavior is essential for its success."

For technology to transition and sustain a company as a remotefirst (or fully distributed) project, leadership requires a clear vision and the skills to communicate this mission. My experience and my interests live at exactly this intersection between technology and leadership.

Combining a technical background with leadership experience, I know first-hand how to design and apply methodologies to maximize the power of the team and how to mentor, support and motivate those around me to follow my lead. Risk assessment and bold decisions are two sides of the same coin, and I thrive on optimizing existing workflows or trying a completely new approach if needed.

Open to new opportunities as Platform Engineer, Cloud Solution Architect or collaborations as DevOps Consultant (remote only).

## Experience

#### Parser

Site Reliability Engineer/DevOps Engineer October 2021 - Present (1 year 3 months)

Working for Moody's Analytics division

## Main Duties:

- Strategize, plan and execute monitoring in a ML microservices/serverless architecture.
- Issue resolutions, working closer with the developer team.

- Infrastructure orchestration with Ansible and Terraform.
- Every day cross-team collaboration, ensuring reliable systems and ops support.
- Runbooks and procedures documentation.

#### ## Technologies

- Infrastructure: AWS, Docker, Kubernetes
- IaC CI/CD: Ansible, Terraform, GitHub, GitHub Actions.
- Monitoring: Prometheus, Grafana, Loki, Graylog, Icinga, PagerDuty, CloudWatch.
- RabbitMQ, ElasticSearch, Apigee
- MLOps: Databricks, MLFlow, Machine Learning, Python

#### Semtechnologies

Tech Lead and Consultant January 2013 - Present (10 years) Spain

#### # Main Duties #

- Cloud Architecture and migration from on-premise.
- Solutions architecture for each particular case.
- Leading the implementation and transition to remote first culture.
- Finding IT solutions for business problems.
- Acting as an interpreter between business needs and technological reality.
- Critical IT support and design disaster recovery strategy.

## Barcelona Graduate School of Economics Senior Cloud & System Architect June 2016 - February 2022 (5 years 9 months)

Barcelona Area, Spain

#### ## Main achievements

- Lead infrastructure migration from bare bone to cloud
- Lead migration from on-site company to full remote company
- Lead strategy and operations in COVID

#### ## Main Duties:

- Setting the technical strategy ensuring alignment with business goals
- IT research and consultancy, responding quickly to new trends, changes and business needs.
- Ops and infrastructure support (Jira Service Desk & Confluence)
- Leading project IT management (Agile, Jira)

- Written/visual documentation for new technologies and procedures (Jira & Confluence)
- Admin server apps, perimeter firewalls, security, planning disaster recovery strategies and backup plans.

#### ## Methodologies and Technologies

- Methodologies: Remote first, OKR, Agile.
- OS: Windows 2012 R2, Debian, Ubuntu, CentOS.
- Infrastructure: VMWare, AWS, GCP, Docker, Kubernetes, GitHub

#### Ciber

Service Engineering - Orange Spain R&D April 2012 - May 2013 (1 year 2 months)

#### ## Main duties

- Validating the quality of new technologies.
- Ensuring the proper functioning of low levl protocols.
- Developing the integration of new services and equipment.
- Investigating key cases and reporting bugs.

#### ## Technologies and protocols

Wireshark, CISCO, CPEs, DSLAM, Voice Services, SIP, DHCP, PPP, IPTV, DLNA, M2M, GPON, Alcatel-Lucent IMS

#### Iss iMedia

System and Security Administrator & Technical Support May 2011 - November 2011 (7 months)

Prat de Llobregat

#### ## Main Duties

- Administration of a visual communication company, ensuring quality of service.
- Managing Windows Server 2008, macOS, CentOS, Cisco and Asterisk.
- Giving both help desk support and working with the highest critical functions.
- \*The company ceased operations in Spain for 2012

#### Xifring

IT Consultant
May 2010 - May 2011 (1 year 1 month)

Barcelona

#### ## Main duties

- Consultancy and research of new technologies for business needs.

- Implementing a variety of technological solutions.
- High level technical support.
- Systems and networks administration.

# Teamlog Iberica 1º and 2º level network technician February 2010 - April 2010 (3 months)

Prat del Llobregat

Working for HP client giving worldwide support (Fortum, Ericsson or Santander Bank). 1° and 2° level network problem solving using Cisco and Juniper firewalls tecnologies.

\*This was a temporary job.

#### Self-employed

IT Consultant & Technician
June 2008 - December 2009 (1 year 7 months)
Royal Leamington Spa

Offering IT services to many clients, particulars and companies. Backups, 24/7 emergency assistance, system administration, security auditory and technical consultancy.

## Education

Warwickshire College

National Diploma in IT Support, IT · (2007 - 2009)

Warwickshire College

National Diploma in IT & Business, IT · (2007 - 2009)

IES Fuente San Luis

FP Superior Programación, IT Programming · (2006 - 2007)